hi there I'm Luis Gomez with palo alto education
大家好 我是palo alto教育的Luis Gomez
and i'd like to share with you
我想和你分享
an awesome application of machine
一个有关机器学习和
learning and neural networks
神经网络的应用 真的超棒的
this topic is called style transfer and what this
这个主题是风格转移 它能够
allows us to do is transfer the style of
将一个图片的风格
one image onto another image
转移到另一个图像上
here you see this really cool gif of an image
屏幕上这张非常酷的动图
changing in real time and as that image
我们可以看到这张图
changes its style is being applied to
风格正在被应用到
the style of the man who's drawing so
那个画画的男人的图片上
that's a really cool gif right there
很酷吧 而且它也让我们直观地
and gives you an idea of what we can do
看到我们通过风格转移能够
with style transfer technology
做些什么
here are the major contributors to this tech
这里就是这项技术的几位主要贡献者啦
we've got Leon Alexander and Mattias who
Leon Alexander和Matthias
all published this paper jointly called
他们联合发表了一篇研究 名为
a neural algorithm of artistic style
a neural algorithm of artistic style（艺术风格的神经算法）
it's a little bit wordy and if you have
文章有点长 所以如果你有
a few hours you should definitely chew
好几个小时的空余时间的话
through that because it's a super
那你一定要读一下 因为这是一篇
interesting paper but you got to set
非常有趣的论文 但你必须要
aside some time for that one
留出挺多的时间来读哦
here we've got some pretty applications of style transfer
这里呢我们有一些关于风格转移的应用
we've got the Prisma app which
首先是Prisma
started to popularize this a lot more
它使这个技术让更多的人知道了
and it's really cool as you've real-time
当你实时地转动
rotate around with your selfie camera
自拍相机
you've got the style of some piece of
然后你就可以把艺术图片的风格
art applied to your video and we've got
应用于你的视频上啦
a similar thing going on with that
我们的技术也已经应用于
360 image art app and yeah
360 Image to Art啦
style transfer is just awesome to look
风格转移真是看看就觉得超棒了
at here I'm not gonna one run through
在这里呢我就不把所有的
all these videos there's quite a few
放一遍啦 因为视频真的是
videos in this presentation that you
蛮多的 你可以
should watch on your own because they're
自己看一下 因为它们真的
super entertaining but here we've got
都非常有趣了 但屏幕上呢展示了
some oculus VR painting for you and yeah
一些Oculus VR（虚拟现实）的图片
it's just pretty to look at man it's
真是光看看
just just really cool to look at
就觉得很酷
so how do we do this how do we accomplish this
那么 我们这样做是如何做到这一点的
well we use something called a
我们使用的东西叫做
generative adversarial neural network
生成对抗神经网络
try and say that one 10 times fast I bet you can'take
哈哈你试试能不能说的比我快十倍 肯定不能吧
okay this this is where it starts
好啦 是不是看起来就好像
to get confusing so the idea behind it
有点复杂呀 但是它背后隐含的
the basic idea behind it it's actually
基本理念实际上并
not that difficult so we've got two
没那么难  这里呢有两个
neural networks if you've seen any of my
神经网络 如果你之前看过我的
previous videos on neural networks
关于神经网络的视频
before then you have an idea of what
那么你应该已经知道什么
we're gonna do here but if you haven't
我们会做什么啦 但如果你没有看过
that's totally fine too we're gonna
也完全没问题 因为我们都是要
learn regardless
重新学习的
so we've got a generator neural network
我们有生成神经网络
and a discriminator neural network now
和判别神经网络
an analogy that's used a ton and is
有一个大家都在用的比喻哦
super helpful for everyone in the
对所有机器学习领域的人都
machine learning community is to think
非常有用 那就是把
of the generator as like a counterfeiter
生成网络想象成就像一个伪造者
and to think of the discriminator as
然后把判别网络视为
like a bank official or something like
银行工作人员之类的身份
that whose job it is to prove the
他的工作就是要证明
counterfeiter is making fake images so
伪造者伪造了图像
yeah these two are pitted against each
是的 这两个之间是相互对抗的
and over time the discriminator
随着时间的推移判别网络
learns more and more to distinguish a
学会越来越多区分
fake image and the generator gets better
假图像的方法 而生成网络就会变得越来越会
and better at tricking the discriminator
骗过判别网络啦
so what is the generator how does the
那生成网络到底是什么呢 它又是
generator work well I talked a little
如何运作的呢  刚刚我已经说了一些
bit about neural networks just now well
关于神经网络的的东西了
a generator is just a neural network and
它是一个神经网络
you feed it just random just garbage
你向它输入一些随机的东西 什么乱七八糟的东西啦
just noise and it will output an image
噪音啦都可以 然后它就会输出一个图像
now this image that it generates is
现在它生成的这个图像
counterfeit it is the generated image
是假的 是一张生成的图片
and let me talk a little bit about what
现在让我们来看一下
this latent sample is so if you've never
图像的隐式表示 如果你之前没有
seen this representation of a number
看过类似这样的数字化表示
before that's totally fine it's really
这很正常啦
rare to see outside of you know out of
因为除了在机器学习里 是很少能在
machine learning so here is what that
其他地方看到这个的
so here is what that image is trying to show so we've got a
这里有一个图像 我们来看看图像传递了什么意思吧
number 1 drawn here and you can see
在这里是数字“1”
here is like a number and array representation
边上呢这个数字“1”的
of this number so all
二维数组显示
these zeros correspond to all the white
右边这些零对应于左边空白
pixels in this image and these dark gray
的部分 右边这些深色的也就是
and all these values that are above zero
这些数值是大于0
but lower than one these represent the
小于1的代表左边
gray and black pixels in this image so
图像中灰色和黑色像素的部分
this number eight right here could be
所以啦这个数字”8“也可以
represented in a similar way as that
以类似的方法显示出来（被老师挡住啦）
number one we just saw using a big array
就像刚刚的”1“一样啦用
of numbers between 0 and 1
0到1之间数组来显示
so what we do is we pass the generator just these
我们做的呢就是向生成网络输入这些
random noise values and we want it to
随机的噪声值 然后希望生成网络来
generate some image like that number 1
产生像刚刚数字”1“一样的图像
and it does that just by picking values
它选择
between 0 and 1 and placing them in the
0到1之间的数值 并将数值放入
right spots so that's how it would work
相应正确的位置 所以它就是通过使用数值来
with numbers and a similar way would
运作的 而通过使用图像也是
work with images
类似的
so that's the generator the counterfeiter
这就是生成网络为什么在我们的比喻里被称为
going back to that analogy and now we
伪造者啦 我们接下来再来看看
go to the bank official or the
去银行工作人员这个比喻吧
discriminator the one whose job it is to
也就是判别网络啦 它的工作就是
tell that those images pass to it are
判断所传递的图片是真的
fake or real so the way the
还是假的 所以
discriminator works well it's just a
判别网络的运作就是一个
basic classifier neural network
基本的分类器神经网络
I say basic but it's not that basic but we're
虽然我说它是基本的 但它也不是那么基本啦 但我们
gonna gloss over that for now because we
现在就不去深究啦 因为我们
just want to get the ideas of machine
只是想要了解机器
learning right we want those
学习的理念 我们只需要那些
fundamentals because the lines of code
基础知识  因为代码
will change the tools that people will
是一直在改变的 人们使用的工具
use will change over time but these
也会随着时间而改变 但是这些
ideas ok these are super important ideas
想法和理念才是非常重要的
that are helping a lot of people in the
因为此时此刻 它们正在帮助世界上的
world right the second
很多人
so the discriminator is a basic classifier
所以判别网络是一个基本的
neural network model and all it does is
神经网络分类模型 它所做的就是
just try to tell if an image is real or fake
试着判断图像是真的还是真的
so if you've seen any of my
如果你看过任何一个我
previous videos we've talked a little
以前的视频 我们已经谈了一点
bit about neural networks trying to tell
关于神经网络的知识了 我们聊过关于区分
like a dog and a cow apart trying to
狗和牛了 就是通过传递图像
identify them when passed an image and
来识别它们
the way it does that is you pass it a
区别的方式就是 你要输入
bunch of images and they have to be
一堆它们图像 并将它们
labeled so you're throwing a bunch of
标记 也就说你要向
images at the neural network and you're
神经网络输入大量的图像
labeling them so like throw an image of
然后标记它们 比如说你输入了很多
dog and make sure it comes with the
狗的图像 然后标记它们为
label of dog throw an image of cow make
”狗“ 然后输入大量牛的图像
sure it comes with the label of cow and
标记为”牛“
you're throwing these labeled images
你把这些标记好的图像
into the neural network feeding it over
输入到神经网络里
and over and over again and over time
逐渐地
it learns to extract features like curves
它学会提取特征 比如边缘曲线啦
and lines and like distances between
线条啦 眼睛之间的距离啦
eyes and lengths of face and things like
脸的长度啦 或者其他类似的东西
that and over time it gets really smart
随着时间的推移 它变得非常聪明
and it learns what in images
它现在可以学习图像中的内容
now instead of having two classes or instead of
而这次呢不像以往的神经网络
having classes like animals like dogs
我们并不设置像”动物“或者”狗“
and cats and cows like we might have
或者”猫“这样的分类
seen before with neural networks we're
这样的分类我们之前可能已经见过了
only gonna have two classes okay this is
这次呢我们只有两个分类
also called a binary classifier because
也称为二元分类器因为
we've only got two options here and the
我们只有两个选择
two options are real and fake so
分别是”真“和”假“
obviously it wants to be able to tell
显然 我们希望它能够判断出
that the generated images are fake and
生成的图像是假的
that the training data that we pass it are real
传递的训练数据是真的
so let's put this all together
好了 现在让我们来看一下宏观
with this really nice imagery right here
的图吧
so we've got our pull that pointer up
等我把鼠标调出来一下
we've got our latent sample right here
我们的潜在样本在这里
just random noise being fed into the
是一些随机的杂声 然后把它们输入
generator the generator does some neural
生成网络里 然后生成网络做了一些神经
network stuff on it and spits out a new
网络的工作 并输出一个新的
image this is a really stupid neural
图像 好吧它确实还是一个很笨的神经
network okay it's really dumb right now
网络 真是太笨啦
because it hasn't had a lot of training
因为现在它还没有经过很多训练
to go off and this discriminator right
好啦 再来看这个判别网络
now is also pretty dumb this is the
现在它也还是相当愚蠢的 现在呢还处于
beginning stages so it might not even be
开始阶段 所以它甚至不能
able to tell the difference between this
区分这个
and this image so as this generator is
和这个啦  一方面呢 生成器不断地
generating images and passing it into
生成图像并将其传递给
the discriminator we got training data
判别网络  另一方面呢我们有训练数据
over here and we're pooling samples out
并从中汇集样本
of it and also passing that to the
并将样本传递给
discriminator so over time it's getting
判别网络 所以随着时间的推移 它会接收到更多的
trained on real data fake data it's
真假数据的训练 它会接收到
getting real data and then fake data and
真实数据和伪造的数据
it's trying to distinguish which one is
在这个过程中 它试图区分哪个是
real which one is fake and over time it
真的哪一个是假的 随着时间的推移呢
learns the difference and as the
它逐渐了解到两者的区别
discriminator gets smarter the generator
判别网络变得越来越聪明 生成网络
starts making better and better images
也能制作出更具有
which are more likely to fool a discriminator
欺骗性的图像了
here's a cool little video
这里有一个很酷的小视频关于
of the discriminator and generator being
判别网络和生成网络
trained and you can see that their
的训练 你可以看到它们的
curves are getting super close generated
曲线越来越接近
generated data is starting to get super close to
生成的数据开始越来越接近
that real data right there and
真正的数据
as it gets closer and closer that
当两者越来越近
discriminator is going to get fooled
这意味着判别网络越来越容易被
more often which means the generator is
欺骗 也就意味着生成网络
going to be putting out better and
生成的图像越来越接近
better more real looking images so
真实的图像
here's an example of style transfer
这里有一个风格转移
being used
被应用的例子
we've got just random noise right here
这里有一些随即噪声
and we're applying the style of this
我们正在将使用
beautiful classic van Gogh starry night
梵高经典之作”星夜“的风格
and here's an example of what the image
这是图像在经过
might look like after one layer of the
一层
neural network of the generator neural network
神经网络生成网络之后的样子
here's an example of the next
这是下一层的样子
layer the next layer and at this final
然后再往下一层 在最后
layer you can see it's starting to
一层的时候 你可以看到它
really have the similar have a similar
变得非常非常像
vibe to this starry night image and on
”星夜“的风格了
the bottom here we get a similar type of
往下看哟 在底部我们有一个相似的
thing where instead of a picture of
的东西 这不是
starry night we've got this picture of a
星夜啦 这里是一张
house and we start to see it get wrapped
房子的图片 我们可以看到慢慢的
as the style is transferred on to that image
这个照片变得很像星夜的风格
so here's some must-reads in
这是一些有关计算机视觉的
computer vision so computer vision is
必读书目 计算机视觉是
the topic of all kinds of all kinds of
所有机器学习任务的关键
machine learning tasks and trying to get
它能够让
computers to play around with images so
计算机进行很多有关图像的操作
yeah these are some good books on the
这里呢 都是一些这个主题的
topic and will help you understand much
好书 会帮助大家了解更多
more of the context behind generative
有关于
additive behind generative adversarial neural networks
生成对抗神经网络的知识
here's a really cool
这是一个超酷
really entertaining video on AI and art
的有关人工智能和艺术的视频
I approve of the music I'll let you
这个音乐我超喜欢的 但是这个视频呢
watch that on your own time
大家在空余时间自己看吧
super entertaining really short - it's only
真的很有趣 也很短
like five minute video and
大概只有五分钟吧
here is more of a keynote type of speech about this
这里还有一个有关风格转移技术
the style transfer technology so if
的主题演讲 如果
you're super interested in you want to
你对这个超级感兴趣
dive even deeper into this I would
你想要学到更深入的东西 那么我
highly recommend watching this talk and
强烈推荐你看一下这个演讲
finally here's some more applications of
最后这里是一些关于
style transfer it's not just used to
风格转移的应用 它不仅仅只是应用于
transfer like famous paintings on to
将名画风格转移到
some regular image it can also be used
一些常规图像上 它也可以
to enhance regular old photography so
使一些老照片重焕生机
here we've got this sunken Solon field
这里有一张沉没的Solon领土的照片
right here and here we've got this
在边上呢 是一张
beautiful rich vibrant field with a nice
美丽富饶充满活力的田野的图片 中间还有
big red log cabin in the middle and by
红色小木屋呢
using style transfer we can brighten up
在使用风格转移之后呢 我们可以把
this image make that grass look more
第一张图片整个变得明亮啦 草看起来
lively and give that sky a really nice
更加鲜艳 天空也变成非常好看的
deep blue color and we can also do
深蓝色  同样地
something like this where we have a
这里还有一张比较淡的
light image and we apply to it a
图像 我们要用旁边这张
beautiful sunset landscape with deep
美丽的日落景观图片里的
reds and deep purples and apply that
深红色和深紫色 然后将图片风格应用在
style to the image to make it look like
上面 看到了吗 这张图片现在看起来
it was taken at night in this
是在晚上拍的 充满了
otherworldly magical location yeah
神奇的魔幻色彩吧
I thought this was pretty funny
真真是有趣极了
style transfer can also be used to transform
风格转移也可以用来改造
furniture designs maybe IKEA is already
家具设计 哈哈说不定宜家早已经
on the neural network hype I don't know
涉足神经网络领域了呢
so those are a lot of really cool
所以刚刚那些呢都是很酷的
applications of style transfer and
风格转移的应用
I think it'd be really great if we
要是我们自己能训练自己的
make our own right now if we could train
风格转移神经网络的话
our own style transfer neural networks
不就更酷了吗
so we're gonna use this thing called
所以我们要用这个叫做
DiscoGan now this is a pretty recent
“DiscoGan”的东西 它是最近新出的
one so it should give us some really
所以应该可以给我们
cool looking results and here's a
很酷的结果 这里一个
flowchart of the basic process
我们基本流程的流程图
we're going to go through so I'll let you look
大家看一下
over that and start thinking about how
然后我们开始考虑接下去
we're gonna do this and I'm gonna pull
要怎么做  现在呢我要打开
my environment up and we're gonna run
我的电脑 我们来打一些
through some code live
代码吧
（此处无内容 请直接快进至12m27s处）
all right so let's get into this live
好的 现在让我们一起
coding to do some style transfer using
编码来用神经网络完成
neural networks so we're not gonna do
风格转移吧 但是今天呢我们不会
Gans today just because the code is
来做Gans 因为这个的代码真的
super crazy to look at and to think
是超级难
about so instead of training two neural
所以我们并不是学习如何训练两个神经
networks to fight against each other
网络互相敌对
like we talked about earlier what we're
就像我们前面谈到的我们
gonna do is we're gonna use one neural
要做的是我们是用一个神经
network to mix together two images this
网络将这两个图像混合在一起
is gonna be great for you guys and
这个就已经很棒了
you'll be able to still see some real
你还是能够看到
examples of styles transfer happening
当你运行这个代码 风格转移在
right under your fingertips as we run this code
你的指尖下发生
holding shift and hitting
按住“shift”然后点击
enter allow you to run a cell here so
“enter”来运行一个代码块
just make sure you hit shift enter and
好啦大家按了“shift“&“enter”
that'll take you through each cell so
之后呢就能看到这里啦
let's start off with cell one right here
我们先从这第一个看起
and we run this and we see it shows us
在运行之后呢 我们可以看到
this nice big image of content style and
三张图片 分别是“内容” “风格”和
mixed images so this is a super helpful
“混合图像” 这是一个非常有帮助的
graphic to refer to and gives you a
例子来大家一个
really good idea of what we're gonna be doing today
直观的感受有关于我们今天要完成的东西
so we've got our content
我们有内容
image and our style image and these are
图像和风格图像 将它们
both being fed into the neural network
都输入到神经网络
so the neural network is going to be
神经网络会从
extracting lines and curves from our content image
内容图像中提取线条和曲线
and it's going to be
然后从
extracting textures and colors from our
风格图像中提取纹理和颜色
style image and it's going to be running
纹理和颜色 随后
these through neural network extracting
神经网络处理这些
features and it's going to be adding the
特征并将
the features that it extracts it's going
对提取到的特征
to do something called calculate a gradient
进行梯度计算
and it's going to use these gradients
利用这些计算后的梯度
that it finds to update this
下方这张
blank image which will slowly over time
空白图像会慢慢地
turn into a mixed image containing the
显示出一张新图片 图片的线条来自与
lines from this content image and the
内容图片
textures and colors from the style image
而纹理和颜色则来自于风格图片
so here we've got our imports very
这里我们要输入一些东西啦
important so we've got to import this
首先非常重要的就是
right here matplotlib inline this just
在这里输入”%matplotlib inline”
allows us to display images like this
有了这个我们就可以在这个窗口
one in this notebook instead of popping
直接显示图像而不是弹出
out a separate window so that's all that does
单独的窗口
import matplotlib this is allows us
导入“matplotlib” 库 它让我们能
to do graphing and displaying images
在这个窗口里 图形和显示图像
like I said within this notebook that
做图形和显示图像
we're in here tensorflow is a library by
再下一行是 “tensorflow”是谷歌的
Google which allows us to do a lot of
一个软件库 它使得我们做很多
common neural network tasks super easily
常见的神经网络任务变得非常容易
so that's gonna save us a lot of work
这会为我们节省了大量的工作
numpy allows us to do matrix math
“numpy”能让我们做矩阵数学
and that's just complex number
这是一个复杂的数字
operations which we have like squares and
操作 比如有数字平方
blocks of numbers instead of just like
数字块 不是像
one number times one number so this
一个数字乘以一个数字这样简单
so this allows us to do those matrix matrix operations
允许我们做矩阵运算
and pillow which we import as
然后就是“pillow”但我们输入的时候
PIL.Image is just a library which
是输入“PIL.Image”
allows us to do common image tasks in
它能帮助我们Python里完成
Python and vgg 16 which is our final import
常见的图像任务 最后是 “vgg16”
here is something that the author
“vgg16”是作者为我们
has created for us and it is a wrapper
创造的 它是一个包装
oops
哎呀 卡了
it is a wrapper not like M&M it is a
哈哈哈它不是MM豆的包装啦 它是
it's a it's a simplification that allows
它是一个简化装置 使得
us to create this vgg 16 neural network
创建这个vgg16神经网络这个过程变得
super easily and what this is is just
超级容易 它就像是
like a it's just a type of neural
一种神经
network and is used commonly when
网络 经常被用于
working with images so the author created
与图像相关的工作 所以作者
of this of these files created us a nice
给我们创建了一个很好的
vgg 16 module that we import here that
vgg 16模块 我们在这里要导入它
allows us to create a big neural network
它会帮助我们创建一个大的神经网络
used for working on images super easily
用于更好更轻松地处理图像
so that's what vgg 16 does
这就是vgg 16的功能啦
so now we're going to get into like the appetizer
接下去呢我们要来完成一些前期的小代码 就像开胃菜一样
code alright this is gonna be all the
这些代码
helper functions that are gonna let us
的功能就是帮助我们
feed our neural network in a super
以始终一致的方法来
consistent way
训练我们的神经网络
so load image uses our our image library
用我们的图像库“Pillow”加载图像
our pillow this PIL.Image library that
就是这个“PIL.Image”
I talked about and what it's gonna do is
它能够
load images in a very specific way it's
以非常特定的方式加载图像
going to load an image it's going to
它会把要加载的图片
resize it to the proper size and shape
调整到适当的大小和形状
and it's going to allow us to have all
这使得我们的图片
of these images in the same exact format
有相同的格式
this is super important when working
这在神经网络运作中式非常重要的
with neural networks any data you feed
任何输入的数据
into it you typically want it to all be
都需要有
the same type of format so same shape
相同格式 相同形状
same file extension
有同一文件扩展名
all that good stuff so that's what load image does
这就是“load image”（加载图片）所做的事情
save image gets us the file
然后是“save image”（保存图片） 这一步骤使得图片的
extension of JPEG and makes sure that
文件扩展名是“JPEG” 并确保
all the images have the same color
所有图像都具有
values all the same range of color
相同范围的颜色值
values so that we've got the same exact
所以所有被输入到神经网络中的
type of images being fed into the neural network
图片都是同一个类型的
plot image big just allows us to
“plot image big”能够让我们
plot a big image inside of this notebook
在计算机中绘制一张大图
and this is what we're going to use to
这是我们用来
display our final mixed image with the
显示最终风格转移后
style transfer to it
的混合图像
plot images this is just to
“plot images”是为了
display images nicely at the very end so
显示最终图像
now we get into the meat of the neural
好了现在让我们开始正餐啦
network code here so loss functions are
首先我们要来看一下“loss function”损失函数
a super important topic to learn about
这是一个值得学习的重要主题
and we're not going to go into all the
而我们不会学习所有的
math but I'm going to give you a good
数学 但我会好好介绍一下
idea of what loss functions are and why
损失函数是什么以及为什么
they're used so we give our computer a
我们要用到它  我们给我们的电脑一个
general direction and using a loss
总体方向 而机器学习算法能够
function machine learning algorithms are
通过损失函数来
able to to get closer and closer and
越来越接近
closer to that goal over time so the
我们设定的目标
loss function we're gonna be using here
我们在这里将使用的损失函数
is mean squared error alright
是均方误差
so let's get into the real meat of all this
现在让我们来深入了解一下
neural network style transfer code
神经网络风格转换代码
so this create content loss function is
这个创建内容损失函数
pretty important so we're gonna walk
非常重要 所以我们要
through it pretty much line by line so
一行一行地来学习
you already know by the name of the
通过的名字我们已经大概知道
function that it's going to have
它与
something to do with a loss function
损失函数有关 它将会被用于
which is used to optimize in neural
优化神经系统
networks and it's also going to have to
网络 它也与
do with our content image specifically
我们输入的内容图片
and the content image remember is the
大家还记得吗 我们将从内容图片上
image that we're gonna get the curves
提取要得到曲线和线条
and lines from in our final style
来体现在最终风格
transferred image just by the name of
转移后的图像上 所以光是看名字我们
this function we already know a lot
就能大概知道它的
about what it's going to do but let's
功能了 但是让我们
dive deeper into the code and see
来更深入地学习一下代码
exactly what's happening here
看看到底它能做什么
so this feed dict line what this is doing is
我们先看到“feed dict”这一行代码
it's telling the neural network very
这一行的功能是告诉神经网络
explicitly hey we're going to feed you
嘿 我们要输入图片啦
an image and the image we're going to
这个图片就是
feed you is this content image right here
内容图片哦
and if you're wondering where that
如果你想知道内容图片
content image is coming through well
在哪里
it's right up here it's going to get
看 就在这里
passed into this function as we call it
我们要把它输入到这个函数
so layers this line right here is going
所以“layers”这一行
to get the the layers that the fed image
会告诉你图像在神经网络中
is moving through in the neural network
所在的层
so here we tell the model hey this is
所以在上面呢是模型里
the image we want to feed to you and
输入的图片
this line is saying hey give me all the
下面这行呢是反馈出来的
layers that this image is going to move through
图片所在的层
now we're going to calculate the
现在 我们要
actual values that the image now we're
计算一下
going to calculate the actual values
图片在通过神经网络
that the neural network calculates when
各层时的
we move the image through the layers of
实际值
the neural network which we received here
我们将在“layers”里拿到数据
so the way we do that is using this
那要怎么来完成呢
super nice tensorflow
我们要用到 “tensorflow”
function just called session.run and
函数“session.run”
all we do is we give it layers and we give
我们要做的就是给它层和
it an image the results of running that
图像 然后图像
image through all those layers that
需要通过的层
needs to go through will be now stored
就会被存储
in the values variable so what this is
在这个变量值里面啦 所以它的功能就是
doing is just making a big placeholder
创建一个大占位符 用来储存
for all the losses we're about to be computing
所有要被计算的损失
and this for loop right here
这里有一个for循环
so remember value is all the values
我们要记住“value”是指
after the image has been passed through
图像通过
all the layers and layer is all of the
所有的层之后的数值 而层是
layers of the neural network that the
指图像要通过的神经网络中的
image is going to be passed through so
所有层
we're going to move through all of these
现在我们要移动
values and layers and we're going to
所有的值和层 我们将
apply a loss function to each layer and
把一个损失函数应用于
each value so we apply that loss
每一个层和值
function store it in this lost variable
然后把这个损失函数储存在损失变量中
and then we toss that into our big
然后我们把它存入我们的
placeholder layer losses
占位符“layer losses”里
so this is actually not going to hold any values
所以现在 它其实没有储存任何数值
for now this is just going to hold loss
它现在只是储存了损失
functions so we're gonna store the
函数
functions that we want to run later in
所以我们现在只是把之后会用到的损失函数
this array and total loss once we've
放进这个数组里 然后看到“total loss”
stored all of those loss functions in
当我们存储了所有这些损失函数
the array and we exit this loop we're
到数组里之后 我们就退出这个“for”循环
gonna hop back out of there and we're
我们只需要
going to just take the average of all
取所有计算出来的
those loss functions and what they
损失函数的平均值
computed and we're going to return this total loss
然后我们要输出这个“total loss”
higher level idea of what this
这个功能更深一点的解释就是
function is doing is it's feeding the
我们把内容图像输入到
neural network our content image which
神经网络中 然后通过它来找到
we want to find lines and shapes of
我们想找到线条和形状的这
it's feeding our neural network with that image
我们把图形输入到神经网络中并使其
through some very specific layers and
通过一些非常具体的层
then it's using something called a loss
然后使用损失
function to calculate an optimization
函数计算使其优化
I don't know how you're going to extract
我不知道它具体是如何提出
features but use this loss function and
特征 但一定要使用这个损失函数
that's your direction all right
这就是你现在的方向和目标啦
so now we're gonna do something similar with
现在呢我们将对风格图像做
the style image so what we're gonna do
类似的操作了 我们要用到的是
is use this thing called a gram matrix
“gram matrix”（格拉姆矩阵）
and we don't need to know exactly what a
我们不需要确切地知道
gram matrix is because that's a big
格拉姆矩阵是什么 是因为这是很难的
linear algebra thing so we're just gonna
线性代数问题 我们要做的就是记住
keep in mind that this whole purpose of
格拉姆矩阵的目的是
the gram matrix is to figure out which
让我们知道当我们输入风格图像的时候
features in the style layers of the
神经网络风格层中的哪一个特征
neural network will activate when we
会被激活
pass it in the style image and then when
所以当我们知道在输入风格图像后
we find out what parts of the style
神经网络
layers in the neural net
风格层中的哪一个部分
are activating when we pass it the style
会被激活
image we're going to copy this into our
我们就可以把这个特征复制到
mixed image and what that does is
混合图像里 总的来说它的功能就是
basically extract all the colors and
从风格图像里提取所有的颜色和
textures from our style image paste that
纹理 并将其
into the mixed image so just like up
应用到混合图像里 就像上面我们看过的
here with the content loss where we're
“content loss”（内容损失）我们在那里
extracting all the contours all the
提取内容图片的轮廓和
lines all the shapes out of our content
线条
image and pasting that into the mixed image
并将其粘贴到混合图像里
here is where this Gram matrix
所以这个格拉姆矩阵
function and this create style loss is
和“style loss”（风格损失）帮助我们
what's going to allow us to copy and
从风格图像中复制
paste the colors and textures from our
颜色和纹理然后粘贴到
style image into the mixed image
混合图像中
all right so this create denoise loss this
我们继续看 这里有“create denoise loss”
is yet another loss function but we're
它也是一个损失函数 但我们
not going to talk about this one because
不打算谈这个  因为它
it's not as important as the other two
没有其他两个那么重要
all that this one does is make the image
它所做的就是使图像
a little bit clearer so we're not going
更清楚一点 所以我们就不
to talk about that for now but make sure
细说了 但是还是要确保我们
to run it again with shift-enter and
用“shift-enter”运行它了
here is where we actually do the style
接下来就是我们实际进行风格
transferring this is what's going to run
转移的地方啦 在这里我们要运行
both of those loss functions that we
我们刚刚创立的两个
created earlier and actually combine
损失函数 我们要将两者结合
them and paste them into our mixed image
并把它们粘贴到我们的混合图像中去
so we're going to use something called
我们要用
gradient descent now gradient descent is
“gradient descent”梯度下降
a way of finding the local minimum and
它能帮我们找到局部最小值
we want to find the local minimum
我们希望通过找到局部最小值来使得
because we want our loss to be as small
我们的损失达到
as possible because when our loss is as
最小 因为当我们的损失达到
small as possible our mixed image will
最小 我们的混合图像会尽可能拥有和内容
have the most of the contours that it
图像相似
can get from our content image and the
的轮廓 以及和
most possible amount of colors and
风格图像尽可能相近的颜色和
textures as it can have from our style image
纹理
so our goal right here is to
所以我们的目标就是
minimize both of those loss functions
尽可能的减少两种损失函数
that we created earlier and the way we
带来的损失
do that is this technique called
我们达成这个目的用到的方法就是
gradient descent so the idea behind
梯度下降了 梯度下降就像是
gradient descent is like if you think of
一个
of like a ball rolling down a hill the
滚下山坡的球
way that a ball rolls down a hill it
球滚下山的方式
doesn't go from like here all the way to
不是直接从山顶
the bottom of the hill right a ball
到达山脚 它是
incrementally rolls down the hill and if
逐渐滚下山坡的
there are like some curves in the
如果山坡上有很多起伏的话
hillside the ball might have to take a
球可能需要通过一条更蜿蜒曲折的
bit of a winding path to get to the bottom
小路才能到山脚
gradient descent is the same idea
梯度下降其实和这个差不多
so except instead of walking down
这里当然不是指滚下山坡而是
Hill we're walking down a like 50
走过五十个
dimensional who knows how many
维度 或者更多个
dimensions to get to the bottom of that
维度来到达
loss function space
损失函数空间的底部(最小损失)
so yeah that's what gradient descent so
没错了 这就是梯度下降了
we're gonna use gradient descent to get
所以呢我们就是梯度下降来
our loss as small as possible to make
尽可能小的损失
sure we can pull as many features as
确保可以从内容图片
possible out of our content image and
和风格图片中提取和提取
our style image to combine them into our
尽可能多来融合到
mixed image so yeah that's the big idea
混合图像里 没错 这就是我们希望通过
with this style transfer function and
风格转移做到的事咯
here you see we're doing our nice tensorflow
接着往下 我们可以看到“tensorflow”
stuff we're going to get the layers
还有“get layers”
of the neural network we want to use
是神经网络中的层啦
which is our we're getting different
我们要从这里得到神经网络中
layers out of the neural network we want
不同的层
to use here and here and these are
这里和这里都有（看老师鼠标）
content layers and our style layers so
这是内容层 还有风格层
we're going to be using different layers
所以内容图像和风格图像
for the content image and the style image
是有不同的层的
and here we make that loss
接下里看到的就是损失
function using those those methods that
函数啦 用到的使我们
we defined above
之前说过的方法
so we've got loss for our content image
所以我们有对我们的内容图片和
loss for our style image and again loss
风格图片都进行了损失函数的操作
for the denoise but we don't want to
当然还有降噪 但是这个
focus on this right now all this does is
就不细说了 因为它唯一功能就是
help the image be a little bit less noisy
帮助图像降噪
so yeah now we're getting the
现在我们
actual variables and in tensorflow what
实际变量 在 “tensorflow”里
a variable is is some value that we want
变量是我们想要
to change so telling tensorflow that
改变的值 所以如果你在tensorflow中
you're making a new variable is telling
设置了一个新的变量
it hey make sure after every iteration
这就意味着告诉它在每一次的
of running those loss functions make
运行损失函数后
sure you update the variables so the
都一定要更新那些变量 所以在这里呢
variables we want to update are the
我们想要更新的变量是
content variables and the style
内容变量和风格
variables because over time we want to
变量 因为我们希望随着时间的推移
be able to pull more and more
我们能够从图像中
information out of these images and we
获取更多的信息
also make a variable for the denoise
当然我们也为降噪设置了变量
just like we did earlier but we're gonna
就像我们之前说过的 我们不会去仔细探究
continue glossing over this because
降噪 因为
remember anytime you see denoise in this
降噪在文件中的
file all it's doing is helping to make
唯一作用就是
the image a little bit clearer and less noisy
使图像更清晰
so now we're going to make a new
所以现在我们要使用“session.run”创建一个新的
tensorflow session using this session.run
tensorflow session
call and all that does is allows
这一步的作用是让
tensorflow to build this big graph of
tensorflow构建
all the mathematical stuff that it needs
它需要做的所有数学问题
to do and we get to do that just one
的一个大型计算图 我们只需要打一行字
line using session.run and passing
就是“session.run” 然后把传入我们要
it the things that we wanted to do
计算的东西 这样就好了
computations on so that's really cool
是不是很酷呢
tensorflow is a real game changer when
所以tensorflow一问世就
it came out so here is where we actually
彻底改变了现状
tell tensorflow how to update those so
好啦 我们继续往下看啦
here is where we're writing the code
这里就是我们编写代码来告诉
that tells tensorflow how much to
tensorflow我们每次
update our variables by and make sure
更新变量的程度 一定要确保是
that it's just the tiniest incremental
最微小的
improvement because we want to descend
改变  因为我们想要慢慢地
slowly okay the big thing with using
下降 在我们使用
gradient descent is if you imagine that
梯度下降的时候还有一件事要注意
if you imagine that ball rolling down a
你想象一颗球滚下
hill example a ball can roll down a hill
山坡的那个例子 这颗球滚下来可能会过头一点点
and then roll back and forth right we
然后又滚回来了 这样反复震荡
don't want that so we want our ball to
但是我们不希望这样的情况发生 我们希望
move a little slower we want it to move
这颗球移动速度慢一点
we want it to move down in tiny little steps
一步步地往下移动
so that it doesn't overshoot and
这样它就不会滑过头
come up the start coming up the other
又从山坡
side of the hill
的另一头开始往下了
here is the part where we're
这里就是我们
going to actually combine those losses
将这些“损失”结合起来的地方了
get that gradient that we calculated up
我们拿到了已经计算好的
here getting all of those tensors
“gradient（梯度）” 、张量
getting all those big big squares of
以及需要
numbers that we want to start updating
更新的大量数字
and store them in this run list variable
并将它们存储“run list”变量里
and mixed image here's where we
接下来 我们看到“mixed image”
initialize our mixed image so all we're
这里呢我们会初始化混合图像 我们做的就是
gonna do with this is make a new big
创建一个新的
block of pixels which will represent a
像素块 代表着
new image and just fill it with random
新图像 并用一些随机的
noise that's all that the mix image is
噪音填充它 这就是混合图像
going to start out as and
开始的地方咯
now we feed our mixed image into the neural network
现在呢 我们把混合图像输入到神经网络中
so that it can start getting all those
它就可以开始获取
features out of our content and style
内容图像和风格图像中
image and yeah and that that's pretty
的特征啦 这就是剩下的
much what the rest of this code does
的代码的功能了
is it feeds the mixed image into the neural
它将混合图像输入到神经
network at the same time as the content
网络 同时内容图像
and style images are going in to
风格图像的
extract their features and
特征被提取
the mixed image is going in right along with them
混合图像与这两个图像一起在程序内
so that it can get applied all of the
这样它就可以将
features that the neural network is
神经网络的提取到的特征
extracting on our other two images and
应用到自己身上
yeah that's it that's all the neural
没错了 这就是所有神经
network code alright cool
网络代码 酷极了
so let's run this
让我们赶紧来运行一下吧
shift-enter so it's okay if you didn't
shift-enter（按住shift 然后点击enter）如果你没有
understand most or any of that really
明白大多数甚至所有的东西也没关系
what I want you to get out of that is
我们想要学习的是
the high-level idea of being able to
一些更高层次的东西 比如说
feed images into a neural network
输入图像到神经网络
trying to think about loss functions and
损失函数
gradient descent and just so you can see
梯度下降等等 而且我们也希望直观展示一下
some of the real-life code that we use
我们在机器学习中用的那些
in machine learning and the real actual
真实的代码和
tools that we use
工具
so and yeah I just want you to expose you to those concepts
所以呢我们是希望向大家展示这些概念
and show you how we use them in real
并告诉大家我们是如何
life code so don't worry if you didn't
编写代码的 所以如果你没有
understand most of that it's totally fine
理解大部分内容的话 也没有关系
it'll take you a while to
要学会这些
understand all this stuff it took me it
还需要很长的时间 我花了
took me along a long time and I'm still
非常非常长的一段时间才学会而且我现在
learning new stuff about this every day pretty much
每天都还在学习新的东西
so here's an example of how
这里呢我将举例给大家看看怎么
to take all that code that we just wrote
用这些我们刚写好的代码
and how to actually run our images right
以及如何正确运行图像
because we never specified like hey take
因为我们其实并没有指定计算机
this style image and take
提取风格图像
this content image
或者内容图像
well this code is going to show you how
那么这段代码将告诉你如何
to actually feed the images that you
输入你想要进入神经网络的
want into that neural network and do all
图片 然后进行
of that style transferring stuff so
风格转移
here's an example we're gonna load this
这里有一个具体的例子 我们会把一张
willy wonka old image and
威利旺卡老年图片上传
that's just stored in this images folder
图片是存储在这个图像文件夹里
and it's called
图片的名字就是
willy wonka old so you can see it's just
“willy wonka old”   我们可以看到我们只要
getting going into that images directory
进入该图像目录
and getting that oops images directory
然后通过图片上传功能
and getting that willy wonka old.jpg image
来上传“willy wonka old.jpg”
using that load image function
“willy wonka old.jpg”
we talked about way back up here to just
这个功能我们在很早之前就说过啦
load that image in a very specific way
我们就是以特定的方式加载该图像
and we do the same thing for our
接下来 我们用同样的方法来上传
style image and this is located in the same
风格图像 风格图像储存在
folder right here and it's just called
相同的文件夹里 名为“style 7”
so let's hit shift enter to load these
所以让我们按住shift点击enter来上传图片吧
we're going to use only the fourth
我们这里只用“vgg 16”神经网络中的
layer of our vgg 16 neural network to
第四层来
get the contours and the lines out of
从内容图像中得到轮廓和线条
our content image this is just like an
这个其实是一个
experimentation thing the author just
实验后的结果 作者呢已经试了
tried a bunch of different layers to see
很多不同的层来看用哪一层
which one was getting the best lines out
能从内容图片中得到
of the content image and it just turned
最好的线条 实验结果显示
out that 4 was the best layer of the
神经网络中的第四层
neural network to extract lines and contours
提取线和轮廓的效果最好
so we're using that fourth layer
所以现在呢我们就用第四层
and now we're getting all of the layers
现在我们看到了所有层
the vgg 16 model has 13 layers
vgg 16模型有13层
and here we're just getting all
我们将把我们的
13 of those layers to run our style
风格图像输入进来并
image through and now we've run our
通过所有的层 现在就要来我们运行
style transfer function and train our
风格转移功能 训练
neural network to transfer the style of
神经网络来进行
one image and to combine the textures
风格转移 它将把一个图像的纹理
and colors from one image and the lines
颜色与另一个图像的线条
and shapes from another image into a
形状相结合 然后将其应用于一张新的
mixed image to create our final style
混合图像来得到我们最终风格转移
transfer result and yeah just run that
之后的图片 赶紧运行吧
and thankfully I have a pretty fast
谢天谢地 我的电脑
computer so I'll just show you the
速度很快 所以我们可以在屏幕上
training right here and yeah we'll see
看一下如何训练 看一下
how all these images are printed out and
如何将所有这些图像显示出来
yeah we'll just watch this train for a
那现在我们就看着屏幕
few minutes
等一会儿吧
all right neural network's done training
好啦 神经网络完成训练啦
and we've got our mixed image
这里就是我们的混合图像
only took me cool final image wow that looks
只花了一点点时间 可是这个图像吧...
really gross
看起来有点恶心
took me three minutes and 52 seconds to
整个过程花了3分52秒
get to this final image
我们得到了这张最终图片
here there you go there's there is chlorophyll infested
惊呆了 这是一个满脸叶绿色的
willy wonka so he took the lines and
willy wonka  所以这张图片的线条和
contours of this image pasted them into here
轮廓被提取然后黏贴到中间的图像上
the colors and textures of this
这张照片的颜色和纹理被提取出
image pasted them into here and we got
粘贴到这里 最后我们通过神经网络的
this really gross looking willy wonka
风格转移得到一张
mixed image using style transfer with a
看着挺恶心的willy wonka
neural network from lines
混合图像
so I want to hammer these ideas into your head of
有一些概念我希望大家要牢牢记住
gradient descent loss functions
梯度下降和损失函数
and I want you to read about them on your own
我希望大家可以自己再去了解它们
because they're super interesting and
因为它们不仅非常有趣
really key to understanding neural networks
也是神经网络的关键
and finally this idea of
最后
packages of help of using code that
软件包 我们用了一些其他
other programmers have written and
程序员写的代码
taking it to help ourselves and you know
来帮助自己
hopefully down the line as we become
希望有一天我们也能变成
better and better programmers we're able
更好的程序员 能够写出
to make our own code our own packages
自己的代码和软件包
that we can share with other programmers
将之分享给其他的程序员
so I want you to take those three things
所以我希望大家能够记住这三件事
gradient descent loss functions and
梯度下降 损失函数和
packages to help the world of
能够让所有人受益
programming get better and I want you to
软件包 我希望大家能
take those ideas and think about them
接受这些想法并认真思考
read more about them on your own time
在自己的空余时间更广泛地阅读
and yeah I hope you enjoyed this live
最后 希望大家能够喜欢这个
coding portion of the style transfer presentation
关于风格专业代码的视频
I am Louis Gomez thank you
我是Louis Gomez 感谢大家
for your time and I'll see you guys
花时间看完了 下次再见吧
later bye
拜拜